Contact

okeyogechivivian@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ogechivivian-5109b2114 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Vault

CyberSecurity Assessment HTML5

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: DevOps Engineer Expert

AppDynamics Verified Core APM

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification

AZ-400 Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Ogechi Vivian

Platform Engineer | Cloud Computing | Site Reliability Engineer | Infrastructure Automation

Germany

Summary

I am a versatile DevOps Engineer with solid experience in Linux Administration and Programming. I have set up and managed CI/CD implementation across the Development and Production environments. I write scripts to automate system updates and deployments, support and work closely with clients to resolve issues and ensure customer satisfaction. I seek opportunities where I can add value, learn and create effective results.

Experience

Interswitch Group

7 years

DevOps Engineer May 2019 - Present (6 years 5 months)

Lagos, Nigeria

- Replication of current infrastructure to the Disaster Recovery Center.
- Configuration and management of load balancing infrastructure.
- Full design and implementation of Kubernetes Clusters.
- Full design and implementation of functional CI/CD pipeline for all projects using Jenkins,

Bitbucket, Spinnaker, JFrog, VMware and Kubernetes.

- Linux/Unix administration for over 600 Unix servers in a hybrid infrastructure.
- Full design and implementation of ELK + Kafka logging infrastructure.
- Daily Process documentation for record purposes.
- Customer support Resolution of escalated issues/tickets using Jira and Service Desk.
- Set-Up and maintenance of SaaS/PaaS products on the cloud (both AWS and Azure).
- Automate server configurations, deployments and upgrades using Python,
 Chef and Ansible on

Azure and On-Prem.

Software Engineer Intern

October 2018 - April 2019 (7 months)

Lagos, Nigeria

- Building microservices with Java Technologies
- Automating deployment pipelines(CI/CD) with Jenkins.
- Fault dockets sign-off and documentation and Customer relationship management.
- Built a Voucher Service for creating vouchers.

Wikimedia Foundation

Technical Writer (Outreachy Intern)

December 2020 - March 2021 (4 months)

Improve and review Lua documentation for MediaWiki

SARU TECH

3 years 2 months

Junior Software Engineer

April 2017 - September 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Benin City, Edo, Nigeria

- Software development, support and maintenance
- Project Management and planning using Trello
- Software version control using github

Web Development Intern

December 2016 - March 2017 (4 months)

Benin-City, Edo, Nigeria

- Building responsive websites using PHP, HTML5, MySQL and Bootstrap

IT Support

August 2015 - November 2016 (1 year 4 months)

Benin City, Edo, Nigeria

- Properly escalate unresolved issues to appropriate internal teams
- Ask customers targeted questions to quickly understand the root of the problem
- Diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues

Subsea 7

Quality Assurance/Quality Control (Intern)

May 2014 - October 2014 (6 months)

Warri, Delta, Nigeria

- Supports the Project Quality Advisor(s) in the alignment of the Company Quality Plan and Systems with Project Contractual requirements.

- Supports project leadership teams in implementing the requirements of the business management system and ensuring contractual compliance throughout the project lifecycle i.e. Engineering, Procurement, Construction and Installation phases.
- Supports the Project Quality Advisor(s) in the coordination of supplier inspection activity and management worksite deployed QC inspection personnel
- Supports the Project Quality Advisor(s) in ensuring supplier and subcontractor inspection and test plans are reviewed, endorsed with Quality requirements and approved.

Education

University of Nigeria, Nsukka
Bachelor of Engineering , Electronic Engineering . (October 2010 - July 2015)